<system>
  <title>Audience</title>
  <slogan>Isolation is a state of mind</slogan>
  <acronym-expansion>
    Achieving Understanding Directly Involving Expertly Nuanced Communication Events
  </acronym-expansion>
  <location></location>
  <short-description>
    Anonymous communication implementation
  </short-description>
  <medium-description>
    Audience indirectly implements a system to communicate anonymously for
    people  who   are  in  need  of  maintaining   contact  but  screening
    communications.
  </medium-description>
  <long-description>
    <p>
      Since this description was last modified there have been major
      additions to the Audience system.  The primary system is an IMAP
      client that is able to read mail and queue actions based on
      programmatic responses to the mail.  The reasoning and usability
      behind this is still at a primitive state but I've written a set
      of filters (actually belonging to the antispam-console system
      but should be refactored into audience).  At any rate it is
      interesting because the system is now at a more advanced state.
      I suppose it would not hurt to allow encryption of these email
      messages.
    </p>

    <p>
      Audience indirectly implements a system to communicate
      anonymously for people who are in need of maintaining contact
      but screening communications.  This functions not only over the
      network, but also for other communication media, such as person
      to person.  A temporary system of ACLs giving permission to
      participate in certain events is used.  In the future,
      permission will be inferred from a KB through Mach.
    </p>

    <p>Network  technologies involved  are  a web  based chat  server,
    freenet,   and    a   freenet   chat   and    mail   system   from
    http://eof.sourceforge.net/,   as    well   as   a    screen   for
    derogatory/hate/negative communications,  and an interface  to the
    Unilang system.</p>

    <p>This IM client is  now operational and integrated with UniLang.
    We  still are  adding features  to  this client  rather than  just
    starting it running now.</p>

    <p>Currently,  Audience uses  a custom  system called  Diplomat to
    guide  behaviour  intelligently.   Diplomat uses  Tabari  to  code
    Audience   communications   into   event  categories.    Then   an
    appropriate response is  generated.  For instance, if  the user is
    insulted,   this    event   is   coded   (and    logged   to   the
    event-system). Diplomat then employs planning wrt goals and social
    rules to determine an appropriate response, currently only using a
    simple state transition table, whereas  in the future we might use
    AI  adversarial  planning  tools.    An  appropriate  response  is
    selected  and generated,  and in  this example,  that would  be to
    demand an apology.  If this failed, relations would be reduced and
    if that failed diplomatic relations  would be ended.  Diplomat may
    probably end  up as either its  own system or in  Mach rather than
    Audience.</p>

    <p>Here  is a  sample of  event types  taken from  Tabari: Accuse,
    agree future  act, agree,  apologize, approve, arrest  person, ask
    information, ask material aid, ask  policy aid, assure, break dipl
    relat, call  for, cancel  event, comment, consult,  criticize, cut
    aid,  cut  routine  act,  decline  comment,  demand,  demonstrate,
    denigrate, deny  accusation, deny action, deny,  discard, endorse,
    expel group, expel personnel, expel, explain position, extend econ
    aid, extend  mil aid,  force, formal  protest, give  other assist,
    grant  asylum,  grant  privilege, grant,  halt  negotiation,  make
    agreement, make  complaint, meet,  mil engagement,  military demo,
    neutral  comment,  noninjury  destr, nonmil  demo,  nonmil  destr,
    nonmil  threat,   offer  proposal,  optimist   comment,  pessimist
    comment, plead, praise, prom material support, prom other support,
    prom policy  support, promise,  propose, protest,  receive, reduce
    relations,  refuse, reject,  release,  request, retract,  retreat,
    reward, seize possession, seize,  specif threat, state invitation,
    surrender, threaten, truce, turn down, ultimatum, unspecif threat,
    urge, visit, warn, and yield.</p>

    <p>Another aspect of audience will be an intelligent communication
    proxy, that will  actually communicate with the user  to give them
    the impression of conversation.   Language models will be produced
    from  my writings  and chat  logs  to interact  with a  yet to  be
    determined  authenticated chat  bot/dialog system  (most  likely a
    hybrid UniLang agent).</p>

    <p>Note that, far  from being a deceptive device,  this agent will
    allow  phenomenal improvements  in  socialization.  For  instance,
    people  equipped  with  MyFRDCSA  can let  their  agents  interact
    autonomously  with other  people's  agents, and  their agents  can
    engage  in a complex  dialog respecting  both users  interests and
    privacy.  In this way, one would not have to constantly go through
    the mundane  process of becoming  aquainted with other  people and
    their  BDIs.   Rather,  the   most  important  concepts  would  be
    forwarded.</p>

    <p>Also, their agents can autonomously "spider" the social network
    by asking for referrals and references by other agents.  This will
    in effect unite the MyFRDCSA  together in a collective format that
    will result in immense improvements in capabilities.  Furthermore,
    with   trust-based  knowledge   sharing  clients,   combined  with
    Clairvoyance for  instance, users  will rapidly become  experts in
    all fields they are interested  in.  This is the mutual power goal
    that  we  are interested  in.   We  are  interested in  maximizing
    everyone's  capabilities  rather  than  capitalizing  on  people's
    weaknesses for personal gain.</p>
    
    <p>Last but not least, it  should be a proxy for communications to
    the outside world,  for instance, for Brainstorm -  so that source
    identity  is  not  revealed  to  parties  who  may  reveal  it  to
    aggressors.  </p>

  </long-description>
</system>
